savethechildren.net 2019-07-24

# Privacy Statement | Save the Children International

Please read this statement carefully to understand how Save the Children International (‘SCI’, ‘we’) collects, uses and stores your personal data.

Save the Children International is a company limited by guarantee, registered in England and Wales with company number 3732267 and a charity registered in England and Wales with charity number 1076822.

The processing of your personal data is carried out by Save the Children International, which is registered with the Office of the Information Commissioner. 

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact:

Data Protection Officer   
Save the Children International  
St Vincent House,   
30 Orange Street  
London  
WC2H 7HH

Email: [dpo@savethechildren.org](mailto:dpo@savethechildren.org) and mark it for the attention of the Data Protection Officer.

This Privacy Statement takes into account several legal instruments including the Data Protection Act 1998 and the General Data Protection Regulation.

**What information do we collect?**

When you interact with us, we may collect your name, address, email address(es), telephone number(s), and, where appropriate, date of birth. 

**How do we collect information?**

We may collect information about you whenever you interact with us. For example, when you contact Save the Children regarding our activities, register as a supporter, send or receive information or sign a petition, you specifically and knowingly provide us with your personal information. We may also receive information about you from third parties – but only if you’ve given them permission to share your information.

**Will we disclose the information we have collected to outside parties?**

We will not share your information with any third party, including Save the Children member organisations for marketing purposes unless we have your consent.

We may share your information with third parties, including Save the Children member organisations and SCI’s service providers if:

  * it is required for the organisation to operate; or
  * it is required to protect our organisation or our beneficiaries; or
  * it is required in order to protect against actual or suspected fraudulent activity; or
  * we are required to do so by law; or
  * we have your consent.

We may also pass your information on to related organisations like other [Save the Children member organisations](http://www.savethechildren.net/contact-us)  so that they may contact you and/or provide further information about the work of Save the Children. By ticking the box “please keep me informed about Save the Children’s work and how I can help via email” you are consenting to this transfer.  If you do not want this to happen, please do not tick the box.  

**How we protect your personal information?**

We take appropriate physical, electronic and managerial measures to ensure that we keep your information secure, accurate and up to date, and that we only keep it as long as is reasonable and necessary.

**What rights do you have in relation to your data?**

You may 

  1. request details of the personal information we hold;
  2. request a copy of your personal information;
  3. withdraw the consent you have provided previously for processing your personal data;
  4. request that we correct or remove the information we have on file;
  5. request that we restrict the processing of your personal information in certain ways; or
  6. object to specific processing of your personal information.

You may make any of the above requests by contacting the Data Protection Officer at [subjectaccessrequest@savethechildren.org](mailto:subjectaccessrequest@savethechildren.org). We shall process your requests unless we have compelling legitimate reasons for not fulfilling such requests.

**Children’s data**

When you register with us, you are stating that you are over 18 years of age or are a minor acting with parental consent. If you are a minor, we need your parental consent as well. If you have any issues with parental consent, please contact us at [dpo@savethechildren.org](mailto:dpo@savethechildren.org). You agree that any information you provide to us about yourself upon registration or at any time is true. 

**Confidentiality**

We cannot be held responsible for the privacy of data collected by websites not owned or managed by Save the Children, including those linked through our website.

**Data retention**

We shall only retain your personal information for as long as is necessary for you to use our services or for as long as you are associated with our work. After such time, we shall only maintain your information for as long as is required or permitted by law.

**Cookie Notice**

Please refer to the Cookie Notice on our website. 

**Notification of change of Privacy Statement**

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Statement. You are advised to visit this website section periodically in order to keep up to date with the changes in our Privacy Statement.

Date of last update of Privacy Statement – 24th May 2018
